Guide to the Mario Ancona Collection
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound
Mario Ancona Collection
1792-1974
ARS-0012
Giacomo Ancona
8 linear feet
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound Stanford University Libraries Stanford, California 94305-3076
The Mario Ancona collection (8 linear feet; 17 boxes) includes photographs, memorabilia, sound recordings and miscellaneous documents related to the baritone's career, and to the performing arts and artists around the turn of the 20th century.
Access
Collection is open for research. Listening appointments may require 24 hours notice. Contact the Archive Operations Manager.
Biography / Administrative History
The baritone Mario Ancona was born in Livorno, Italy on February 28, 1860. After finishing a business career he studied voice with Maestro Matteini in his native city, and later with Giuseppe Cima in Milan. He made his debut as an amateur singer in the Concerto Maglioni, in 1880. Ancona's earliest recorded opera appearance was in 1889 with the Triest opera company, singing the role of Scindia in Massenet's Le Roi de Lahore. Shortly after he sang another Massenet opera, Le Cid, in Milan's La Scala (1890), and two years later he created Silvio in Leoncavallo's Paglicacci. For many years he appeared as a regular artist at London's Covent Garden Opera where he was held in very high esteem. He sang as a guest artist in Cairo, Lisbon, Madrid, Paris, Warsaw, Moscow, St. Petersburg, Chicago, Boston and various cities in South America. From 1906-08 he was engaged with the Manhattan Opera House where he was particularly successful in his role of Don Giovanni. He was much admired on stage for his elegant deportment, and his beautiful and expressive voice, particularly in the high register. His repertory included Verdi (Germont, Rigoletto, Amonasro, Iago and Don Carlos in Ernani), Puccini (Lescaut and Marcello), Mascagni (Alfio and David in L'amico Fritz), Mozart (Don Giovanni and Figaro), Wagner (Wolfram, Telrammund and Hans Sachs), and several French roles such as Nevers, Escamillo and Valentin. After retiring in 1916 Mario Ancona devoted himself to teaching voice. He died in Florence on February 23, 1931.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Mario Ancona collection was created by his son Giacomo Ancona. It was mainly organized in scrapbooks, some bound, others with loose leaves boxed together. The materials gathered range from as early as 1792 with an Ancona family document, to as late as the 1970s with Giacomo Ancona's correspondence. The primary languages represented are Italian and English. Of particular interest are the three oversize portfolios entitled 1. Mario Ancona, 2. Musical Artists and 3. Royalty, Composers, Conductors, Comedians, Virtuosi, Famous People, and Students which contain photographs and documents mounted on poster board. The selection of photographs ranges from autographed portraits of opera singers and composers to members of royalty. Further items include original art work, concert and opera announcements, and honorary documents. Beyond the scrapbooks and portfolios are two volumes of autographed vocal scores entitled Romanze; opera publications; discographies and musical recordings which include 5 reel to reel tapes, 19 non-commercial discs, 17 commercial discs and 2 damaged cylinders.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in ten series: 1. Scrapbooks. 2. Portfolios containing mounted photographs on poster board. 3. Mementos of the Ancona family. 4. Opera materials. 5. Publications. 6. Acknowledgements. 7. Discographies. 8. Scores. 9. Sound recordings. 10. Miscellaneous.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Ancona, Mario,1860-1931.; Baritones (Singers); Musicians--Portraits.; Opera--19th century.; Opera--20th century.
Separated Material
Filed separately is the Giacomo Ancona correspondence documenting the searches for materials pertaining to his father.
Container List
- Portfolios
  - The Times. Court CircularJuly 17, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Windsor Castle. Libretto. Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Amico Fritz July 15, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "State performance at Windsor Castle. Mascagni's Operas."July 17, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Windsor Castle. Program booklet. Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Faust May 19, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Times. Court Circular. Windsor CastleMay 21, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Program. Buckingham PalaceJuly 9, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Program. Windsor Castle. Cowen, Frederic H. (Frederic Hymen), Sir, 1852-1935. Signa July 17, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Times. Court Circular. Windsor CastleJuly 19, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Windsor Castle. Libretto. Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Carmen July 16, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Times. Court Circular. Windsor CastleJuly 18, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Program. Buckingham PalaceJune 22, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Program. Buckingham PalaceMay 28, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Program. Buckingham PalaceJuly 1, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Program. Buckingham PalaceJune 2, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Times. Court Circular. Windsor CastleJuly 6, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letter from Mario Ancona to Mr. Vert (letter of recommendation)May 25, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Thinking of you! Poems dedicated to Emma Dec. 20, 1880, Blue Notebook. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Handwritten love poems in Italian
  - Program. Buckingham PalaceJuly 2, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Program. London (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Era Lucia, a poem from the Romanza. Written on the verso of a concert program.
  - Letter from Giuseppe Cima, maestro di M.A. to Mario Ancona. Milan Jan. 22, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter from Maestro Vittorio Maria VanzoFeb. 8, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter from Maestro Emilio Usiglio to Mario AnconaNov. 22, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter from Maestro Enrico Bevignani to Mario AnconaNov. 22, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Maestro Charles Halle to Mario AnconaJune 26, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter from Henry Russell, impresarioSept. 14, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Two letters from Ruggero Leoncavallo to Mario Ancona (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter from Ruggero Leoncavallo to Mario AnconaApril 30 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Two Letters from Ruggero Leoncavallo to Mario Ancona (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Two Letters from Ruggero Leoncavallo to Mario AnconaNov. 7, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letter from Ruggero Leoncavallo to Mario AnconaMay 20, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letter from Ruggero Leoncavallo to Mario Ancona (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letter from Charles V. Stanford, composerJuly 25, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letter from Jules MassenetMarch 18, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Two letters from composer Alfred Keil to Mario AnconaMarch 28, 1899 and Feb. 28, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Three letters from Cecile Chaminade to Mario AnconaJan. 12, ? and Jan. 10, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Three letters from G. d' Hardelot, Arthur Sullivan and Herman Bemberg to Mario Anconano date; June 27, ?; no date (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Two letters from Umberto Giordano and Giacomo Puccini to Mario AnconaJanuary 1898 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Three letters from Luigi Denza and F. P. Tosti to Mario Ancona March 1, 1890; May 14, ?; June 24, ? (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Three letters from Eleonora de Cisneros, Irma Monti de Baldini and Fernando de Lucia to Mario AnconaDec. 1910; no date; Aug. 7, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Three letters from composers Luigi Mancinelli and Frederic H. Cowen to Mario AnconaSept. 9, 1894; Oct. 26, 1894; May 17, ? (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Three letters from sopranos Emma Calve, Adelina Patti and Nellie Melba to Mario Anconano date; May 29, 1905; no date (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Three letters from composer Richard Barthelemy and impresario H. Higgins to Mario AnconaApril 16, 1925; May 25, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Eight letters from tenor Jean de Rezke to Mario AnconaJan. 15, 1901; Apr. 5, 1900; Feb. 5, 1902; Mar. 11, 1903; April 24, 1903; Apr. 16, 1910; Feb. 6, 1922; Feb. 21, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Letter from Lady Gladys de Grey to Mario Ancona (Box 1, Folder 27)
    "Covent Garden's protectoress. Sister in law of Higgins."
  - Two letters from painter Madeleine Le Maire and impresario Henri Russell to Mario Anconano date; June 30, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Two letters from painter Vittorio Corcos to Mario Anconano date; Mar. 11, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Three letters from author Matilde Derao and Prince Frederik of Prussia to Mario AnconaMar. 1, 1902; Feb. 28, 1902; July 12, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Letter from pianist Enrico Rossi to Mario AnconaJan. 14, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Announcement of Mario Ancona's death, Radio Milan. Lisa SergioFeb. 23, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Two letters from Sophie, Queen of Greece and Guido, Viscout Modrone, president of the Leonardo da Vincino date; May 2, 1931 [?] (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Letter from Senator Alessandro ChiapelliFebr. [?] 23, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Letter from the painter Vittorio Corcos to Mario Ancona (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Four letters from author Ugo Oietti, painters Ulvi Liegi and Oscar Ghiglia, comedian and Sebastiano Lopez to Giacomo Ancona1931 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Condolences
  - The Pathéphone, booklet (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Société des Microphonographes Bettini, booklet (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Société des Microphonographes Bettini, booklet (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - A true Mirror of Sound. Bettini Microphonograph, booklet (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - I Dischi Pathé (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Historical Records. Bettini: Sembrich Cylinder and Three CatalogsOct. 1, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Victor Red Seal Records, booklet (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - New Victor Records; Victor Grand Opera Records March, May 1907, booklets (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - A True Mirror of Sound. Bettini, booklets (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - RCA Victor Record ReviewDec. 1946, booklet (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - New Victor Record CatalogueJuly 1909, booklet (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - List of Red Seal Records. Victor Talking Machine CompanyJan. 1925, booklet (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Edison RecordsJuly 1908, booklet (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - RCA Victor announcement of Heritage Series, leaflet (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Belcanto Disc Catalogue; Stars of the Metropolitan, leaflets (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - C.R.S. Historical Records, leaflet (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bettini Microphonograph and Records, June 1898 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bettini Microphonograph and Records; Record Collector; Top Artists PlattersJune 1898; Sept 1965, booklets and leaflet (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Connoisseurs' Record Club Bulletin #3 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Famous Records of the Past; Rococo Records 1964, leaflets (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Rococo Records. First ReleasesMarch 1964 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Royal Opera Covent Garden. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tristan und Isolde June 30, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Royal Opera Covent Garden, announcement.June, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Royal Opera Covent Garden, announcement. Bellini, Vincenzo, 1801-1835. Norma June 24, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Royal Opera Covent Garden, announcement. Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Don Giovanni June 23, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Program. Stafford HouseJune 26, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Royal Opera Covent Garden, announcement. De Lara, Isidore, 1858-1935. Messaline. July 8, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Royal Opera Covent Garden, announcement. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin June 27, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Royal Opera Covent Garden, announcement. Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Fidelio June 1, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Card with artists' namesJuly 12, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Crafton Galleries. Concert programJuly 12, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 12. Berkeley Square. Program; Seamore Place. Program.July 6, ?; June 7, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Programs: 7 Cadogan Place, S.W.; Mr. Bagby's Musical Mornings1894-1906 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Four visiting cards1893-94 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Four visiting cards1895- (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Five visiting cards1903- (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Four visiting cards1894- (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Five visiting cards1894- (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Invitation by the Princess Letitia di SavoiaMarch 21, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - New Metropolitan Opera House. Four Sunday Night Concert Programs.1894-95 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Vaudeville Entertainment. Round the operas in twenty minutes; Passing Show1894- (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Three Metropolitan Opera House announcements1895; 1896 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Souvenir Opera Season 1893-94, New York., booklet (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Grand Opera program. Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Cavalleria rusticana and Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci April 3, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Libretto. Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci (annotated) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Libretto. Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Faust (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Program. American Academy of Music. PhiladelphiaDec. 4, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Letter of appreciation by The Cunard Steam Company; Program. In aid of seamen's charities April 29, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Concert given by the artists of the Royal Italian Opera, London and the Metropolitan Opera House, New York.
  - Program for the Real Theatro de S. Carlos.Dec. 22, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Program for the Real Theatro de S. Carlos.1904-1905 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Program for the Real Theatro de S. Carlos.1908-1909 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Eight announcements: Manhattan Opera House 1906 - 1908 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Program. Teatro de la Opera. Buenos Aires.1902 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Program. Teatro de la Opera. Buenos Aires.1902 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Program. Boston Opera House1913-14 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Program. Théatre des Champs-Elysées1914 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Program. Boston of Opera House. Season of Grand Opera1913-14 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Announcement: Boston Opera House. Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Rigoletto Dec. 29, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Five visiting cards; Coupon for Amateur Comedy Club (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Grand Opera Season. Chicago. Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Don Giovanni Jan. 19, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Program. Real Theatro S. Carlos1908-1909 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Two visiting cards (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Six Metropolitan Opera House1894-96 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Announcement: Manhattan Opera 1908 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Two programsJune 21 and 22, 1899 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Two programs: Carlton House Terrace; Duddley HouseJuly 23, 1895; June 27, 1895 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Two programs July 19, 1899; June 30, 1899 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Two programs: Charity concert; Carlton House TerrceAug. 28, 1900; July 11, 1900 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Two programs: Harewood House; Scenes from Opera ComiqueJuly 10, and 8, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Program: Grand Naval & Military Concert in Aid of Service CharitiesJuly 6, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Program: Mr. Landon Ronald's Annual Grand Morning ConcertJuly 5, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Two programs: Real Paço d' AjudaMarch 22, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Two programs: Cadogan Place; Carlton House Terrace July 14, and 15, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Two programs: Five O' Clock du FigaroMarch 27, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Programs: Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Barbiere di Siviglia; Photograph of M. AnconaMarch 25, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Program: Norddeutscher Lloyd, Bremen - New York. Schnelldampfer, Kaiser Wilhelm II.April 5, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Acknowledgement: To Mario Ancona distinguished vocal artist performing in maestro G. Verdi's opera Othello. Florence 1913 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Announcement: Irish Club Concert.May 21, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Program: Irish Club Concert.May 21, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Two programs: Soirée Artistique, Paris. Société Italienne "La Polenta"; Liverpool Philharmonic Society April 8, and Oct. 23, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Two letters from Royal House of Portugal Feb. 28, 1904; Feb. 11, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Stafford House FêteJune 26, 1901, booklet (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Program: Madame Rejane's Season, London1905 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Niagara in Summer and Winter (autographed)March 16, 1896, booklet (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Pen and ink drawing with dedicationJuly 27, 1895 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Program: Song Recitals. Chickering HallJan. 2, 1896 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Casa Reale d' Inghliterra, four items1893 -1894 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Ferruccio Busoni1907 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Harold Bauer1907 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Giuseppe Buonamici1907 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Giuseppe Buonamici1907 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Pietro MascagniMay 30, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Pietro MascagniOct. 12, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Program: Théatre Sarah-Bernhardt. L'Opéra de Monte-Carlo. Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Barbiere di Siviglia May 30, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Two Letters from Ruggero Leoncavallo to Mario Ancona (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Program: Windsor Castle. The Royal Opera House, Covent Garden. Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Cavalleria rusticana July 15, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Artistic Memories (Ricordi Artistici), Bound, hard covers, green with gold decorations. 9 1/2" by 13 1/2. Treated by preservation May, 2002 (Box 5)
- Portfolios
  - Two watercolors and four sepia photographs of: Mario M. Ancona's mother, Annetta Gallichi Ancona and Dr. Giacomo Ancona, Mario's uncle. (Oversize 13, Folder 1)
  - Sketch of Mario Ancona painted by Schizzo G. Sanctis, London1897 (Oversize 13, Folder 2)
  - Concert announcement: Romanzas recital. Real Theatro de S. Carlos, LisbonFeb.20, 1899, Poster. Art by Raphael Bordallo Pinneiro (Oversize 13, Folder 3)
    Maestro Ancona, voice and Maestro Campanini, piano
  - Four Sketches (Oversize 13, Folder 4)
    Two watercolors with dedications by Caramba, costume desinger; pencil drawing, Ancona's portrait signed by Albert Lubert, N. Y (probably 1895-96); Caricature of M. Ancona by G. Viafora from the collection of Manhattan Opera House artists.
  - M. Ancona in opera roles: three sepia photographs (Oversize 13, Folder 5)
    Two photographs of Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tannhäuser. Florence 1910; One photograph of Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello
  - M. Ancona in opera roles: one sepia photograph (Oversize 13, Folder 6)
    Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Edgar
  - M. Ancona in opera roles: two sepia photographs (Oversize 13, Folder 7)
    Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello; Ponchielli, Amilcare, 1834-1886. Gioconda
  - M. Ancona in opera roles: two sepia photographs (Oversize 13, Folder 8)
    Ponchielli, Amilcare, 1834-1886. Gioconda; Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864. Huguenots
  - M. Ancona in opera roles: two sepia photographs (Oversize 13, Folder 9)
    Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Roi de Lahore. Trieste
  - M. Ancona portrait: sepia photographOct. 21, 1910 (Oversize 13, Folder 10)
    With dedication: "For you dearest soul. With great affection. Mario". Florence
  - M. Ancona portraits: two photographs, New York (Oversize 13, Folder 11)
  - M. Ancona portraits: pencil drawings (Oversize 13, Folder 12)
    Signed Enrico Caruso, New York, 1907; Naguenet, 1916
  - M. Ancona caricature: ink drawing (Oversize 13, Folder 13)
    Signed by Carlo Bonafedi, Florence
  - M. Ancona caricatures: three ink drawings (Oversize 13, Folder 14)
    Signed by Scarselli, Florence; two ink drawings, artist unknown: M. Ancona singing and M. Ancona with Zelie de Lussan. London, 1901
  - Six photographs (Oversize 13, Folder 15)
    Upper row: M. Ancona, Luigi Mancinelli, de Lucia; only M. Ancona is identified; Jean de Reszke, Edouard de Reszke and M. Ancona; Lower row: M. Ancona, Mimi Bevignani, Enrico Bevignani, Plancon; Photograph by Francesco Manconi. A. Franchetti, M. Ancona, Giacomo Puccini; M. Ancona, Bassi, ?
  - Two photographs (Oversize 13, Folder 16)
    Upper: "Fall 1891. Author and writers of Fritz, together with the commission of organizers for the performance." Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Amico Fritz Lower: Reference to Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Cavalleria rusticana in photograph. Dedication: "A memento to the dear girl Dora Lita Ancona. Livorno, Aug. 14, 1902 (year and signature illegible)." Stagno, Mascagni, Mugnone, Bellincioni, Ancona
  - M. Ancona in opera roles: two photographs (Oversize 13, Folder 17)
    Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello. Florence, 1913; Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Carmen. New York
  - Three photographs (Oversize 13, Folder 18)
    Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Amico Fritz. Cremonini and Ancona. Faenza, 1891; Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Cavalleria rusticana. Bellincioni and Stagno; In Montecatini: Begnani, Ancona
  - Three photographs (Oversize 13, Folder 19)
    Keil, Alfredo, 1850-1907. Serrana. Lisbon; Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Amico Fritz. Cremonini and Ancona. Faenza; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tannhäuser. New York
  - Four photographs: M. Ancona portraits (Oversize 13, Folder 20)
    Photographs taken in Florence, New York, London and Warsaw
  - Two photographs: M. Ancona portraits (Oversize 13, Folder 21)
    Photographs taken in Rome by Bettini; with dedication to "Maria Pia Levi, from a sincere friend, Mario Ancona."
  - Two photographs: group in front of winter landscape (Oversize 13, Folder 22)
    Mario Ancona, Emma Calvé, Albert Lubert, Ile Lubert, Frances Saville, Maurice de Vries
  - Two photographs: group in front of winter landscape (Oversize 13, Folder 23)
  - Oil painting (Oversize 13, Folder 24)
    Male figure identified as Marcello, referring possibly to the character in Alfredo Keil's opera Serrana.
  - Three group photographs (Oversize 13, Folder 25)
    Aboard the ship Crownprince Wilhelm, Bremen. Only three people identified: Charles Dalmores, Amadeo Bassi, Mario Ancona; in train station, USA tour; group in urban setting
  - Two honorary documents, March 4, 1902 and March 9, 1905 (Oversize 13, Folder 26)
    From his Majesty Emanuelle III, Mario Ancona is appointed Knight of the Crown of Italy
  - Two honorary documents, Jan. 27, 1898; March 17, 1904 (Oversize 13, Folder 27)
    From the King of Portugal, Mario Ancona is appointed Knight of the order Sao Thiago.
  - One honorary document, March 9, 1919 (Oversize 13, Folder 28)
    Florence. Military recognition for providing information to the families of militaries.
  - Three photographs: Bellincioni, Gemma, 1864-1950 1890; 1900; 1902 (Oversize 14, Folder 1)
    With dedications
  - Two photographs: Nethersole, Olga, 1870-1951 and Nielsen, Alice, 1876-1943 (Oversize 14, Folder 2)
  - Four photographs: Butt, Clara, Dame, 1872-1936 and Arnoldson, Sigrid, 1861-1943 (Oversize 14, Folder 3)
  - Two photographs: Saville, Frances, 1862-1935 and Lussan, Z#&233;lie de, 1861-1949 1896; 1897 (Oversize 14, Folder 4)
  - Four photographs: Calv#&233;, Emma, 1858-1942 1893; 1894 (Oversize 14, Folder 5)
  - Three photographs: Calv#&233;, Emma, 1858-1942 1896 (Oversize 14, Folder 6)
  - Three photographs: Calv#&233;, Emma, 1858-1942 1894; 1896 (Oversize 14, Folder 7)
  - Two photographs: Melba, Nellie, Dame, 1861-1931 1894, photographs have faded greatly (Oversize 14, Folder 8)
  - Three photographs: Melba, Nellie, Dame, 1861-1931 1893; 1895 (Oversize 14, Folder 9)
  - Five photographs: Abbott Bettini, Daisy; Mantelli, Eugenia, 1860-1926; Borghi, Adele; Mendioroz, Valentina; Palloni, M. A. (Oversize 14, Folder 10)
  - Three photographs: Patti, Adelina, 1843-1919; Cavalieri, Lina, 1874-1944; Melba, Nellie, Dame, 1861-1931 1905; 1907; 1894 (Oversize 14, Folder 11)
  - Two photographs: Patti, Adelina, 1843-1919 1893 (Oversize 14, Folder 12)
  - Five photographs: Joran, Pauline; Engle, Mary; Wyns, Charlotte1896; 1926 (Oversize 14, Folder 13)